Southwest Folklore Center Field Recordings Collection 1943-ongoing
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Audio Recordings, 1943-ongoing; Series I
  - Bert Whetton, Cowboy songs, February 15, 1977; Tape contains interview with and songs performed by Burt Whetton, a Mormon cowboy from the Chihuahua Colonies, Mexico. The interview took place at the V.A. Hospital in Tucson, AZ, where Whetton was a patient. The guitar was loaned by James S. Griffith. Songs include: Old Chisholm Trail -- Trail to Mexico -- Road to Pacheco -- So long, it's been good to know you -- Cross-eyed constipated Mary Jane -- Very unfortunate man -- Utah Carroll... Transcript available in file 84.16/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith and Barney Burns at the V. A. Hospital in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 10 in. (Box 84.16, Folder R.2)
  - Bert Whetton, Cowboy songs, February 15, 1977; Tape contains interview with and songs performed by Burt Whetton, a Mormon cowboy from the Chihuahua Colonies, Mexico. The interview took place at the V.A. Hospital in Tucson, AZ, where Whetton was a patient. The guitar was loaned by James S. Griffith. Songs include: Utah Carroll -- Punchin' the dough -- Mr. Woolworth -- Are you tired of me darlin' -- Did I turn down a better deal -- Texas Rangers -- Jessie James. Collected by James S. Griffith and Barney Burns at the V. A. Hospital in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 10 in. (Box 84.16, Folder R.3)
  - C. A. "Chuck" Lakin, Cowboy songs, August 22, 1984; Tape includes poems and songs with guitar accompaniment performed by Lakin. The tape was recorded at the Lakin Milling Company Office in Tolleson, Arizona. Songs include: Sierry Pete (incomplete) -- Maverick Bull -- Legend of boastful Bill -- Sierry Petes/Tying knots in the devil's tail -- Jake and Rodney -- Peter Gray -- Waltzing Matilda... Transcript and photocopied manuscripts available in file 84.17/M.1. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tolleson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 84.17, Folder R.1)
  - Virgil H. Hamby, "Wild Horse Shorty", Banjo music, August 23, 1984; Tape contains interview with and banjo tunes performed by "Shorty." Songs include: Cripple Creek -- Shortenin' bread -- Darlin' Nellie Gray -- Old Joe Clark -- Whoa mule -- Sally Goodin -- Weeping willow tree -- Old Joe Clark (2)... Transcript available in file 84.18/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 84.18, Folder R.1)
  - Earl Rodgers, Interview, November 15, 1984; Tape contains interview, songs and poems performed by Rodgers of Tonto Flats, Arizona... Cocaine Bill and Morphine Sue -- Thermopolis -- Wyoming -- Sierry Petes -- Streets of Laredo -- A.A. Ranch -- Shag Bronte and Billy the Kid... Transcript available in file 84.23/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith and Warren Miller in Skull Valley, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 in. (Box 84.23, Folder R.1)
  - Gilbert Barrios, Corridos, November 21, 1984; Tape includes corridos sung by Barrios with his own guitar accompaniment... Gabino Barrera -- Corrido de Cananea -- Corrido de Villa -- Caballo Prieto Azavache -- El Corrido del Teniente y Gonzales (also known as "El Corrido de Arnulfo Gonzales" or "Arnulfo") -- Mexico Lindo y Queridor (cancion). Collected by James S. Griffith in Benson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 in. (Box 84.24, Folder R.1)
  - Pachuco conversations, July 2, 1986; Tapes are part of the George Barker Collection, SWF 4, and contain interviews and examples of the Pachuco language used by Tucson youth gangs in the 1940's. Collected by George Barker in Tucson, Arizona. 2 sound tape reels, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. and 10 in.; George Barker Collection. (Box 85.2, Folder R.1)
  - Earl Rogers, Johnny Whelen, Glenn Ohrlin, and Everett Brisendine, Southwest Folklore Center/Student Union Activities Board Cowboy Concert, March 8, 1985; Tape contains stories, songs and poems from a cowboy concert held at the University of Arizona Student Union Ballroom, sponsored by the Southwest Folklore Center and the Student Union Activities Board. The concert was hosted by James S. Griffith. Program was as follows-- Earl Rogers: Yavapai Pete / You ask me were I'm goin'/ Utah trail; Johnny Whelan: Flor de Capomos / Penas Clavadas; Everett Brisendine: Old Cowboys / Christmas in a winter camp; Glenn Ohrlin: Santa Fe trail / Here's to the bull that roams the wood; Earl Rogers: Happy Jack's / Mother, the queen of my heart; Everett Brisendine: Wild Horse / To a little lady. Transcript available in file 85.4/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith at the Student Union Ballroom at the University of Arizona in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 10 in. (Box 85.4, Folder R.1)
  - Earl Rogers, Johnny Whelen, Glenn Ohrlin, and Everett Brisendine, Southwest Folklore Center/Student Union Activities Board Cowboy Concert, March 8, 1985; Tape 2 of 2 contains stories, songs and poems from a cowboy concert held at the University of Arizona Student Union Ballroom, sponsored by the Southwest Folklore Center and the Student Union Activities Board. The concert was hosted by James S. Griffith. Program was as follows-- Glenn Ohrlin: Reincarnation; Earl Rogers: When it's roundup time in Texas /Wild Buckaroo; Johnny Whelan: El Palomito / Juan [Marta?]; Everett Brisendine: Choctaw / In memory of a pardner; Glenn Ohrlin: High toned dance / Frost on the cowboys tarp; Earl Rogers: Little Joe, the wrangler /Empty cot in the bunkhouse tonight; Johnny Whelan: Mothers don't let your babies grow up to be cowboys / El Chubasco; Everett Brisendine: Old timers /Unsung heroes of the West; Glenn Ohrlin: Lee's Ferry. Transcript available in file 85.4/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith at the Student Union Ballroom at the University of Arizona in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 10 in. (Box 85.4, Folder R.2)
  - 2nd Annual All Tohono O’Odham [Old Time] Fiddle Orchestra Contest, Wa:k Pow Wow, March 9, 1985; Tapes contain program recorded at the Second Annual Wa:k Pow wow Old Time Tohono O’Odham Fiddle Orchestra Contest. Performing bands include: the Lester Varvages Band, the Phillip Miquel Band, the Edmund Wilson Band, the Herbert Martinez Band, and the San Simon Old Great Time Band. Mike Enis hosts the concert in English and Tohono O’Odham. A short announcement is made by James S. Griffith. Each group performed a polka, a two-step (choti) and a mazurka. Transcript and related material is available in file 85.5/R.1.T and 85.5/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith and Angelo Joaquin, Jr. at Wa:k Pow Wow at San Xavier Mission in Tucson, Arizona. 2 sound tape reels, analog, 7 in. (Box 85.5, Folder R.1, R.2)
  - Sam Fenner, John Bradley, Marvin Bennett, and "Slim" Luther Kite, Grand Canyon Cowboy Band Concert, August 31, 1985; Tape contains stories, songs and poems from the Grand Canyon Cowboy Band Concert. Introduction by Warren Miller. Songs and poems include: Hell among the yearlings/Ragtime Annie (Bennett) -- The Cowboy's dream (Kite) -- Waltz (Fenner) -- All aboard for the Bright Angel Trail (Bradley) -- Going up to Cripple Creek (Kite) -- Bugler boy (Bennett) -- Waltz (Kite)-- Tumblin' Tumbleweeds (Bradley and Bennett) -- Bad Brahma Bull (Bradley) -- Carry me back to Mammy (Fenner) -- Sierry Petes (Bennett) -- Waltz (Fenner) -- Phantom Ranch dream (Bradley)... Songs and poems are interspersed with stories. Collected by James S. Griffith and Warrer Miller in Elks Opera House, Prescott, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 10 in. (Box 85.17, Folder R.1)
  - Sam Fenner, John Bradley, Marvin Bennett, and "Slim" Luther Kite, Grand Canyon Cowboy Band Concert, August 31, 1985; Tape 2 of 2 contains stories, songs and poems from the Grand Canyon Cowboy Band Concert. Introduction by Warren Miller. Songs and poems include: Mustang with wings (Kite) -- Texas wagonneer (Fenner) -- Flop-eared mule (Kite) -- Moonshine steer (Bennett) -- Soldier's joy (Fenner) -- Vera - the Queen of the Canyon (Bradley) -- Lone star rag (Fenner and Kite) -- Patonia, pride of the plains (Bennett) -- Roll on little dogies (All)... Songs and poems are interspersed with stories. Collected by James S. Griffith and Warren Miller at Elks Opera House in Prescott, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 10 in. (Box 85.17, Folder R.2)
  - Third Annual All O'odham Old Time Fiddle Orchestra, Wa:k Pow Wow, March 8, 1986; Tapes contain performances by the Gu-Achi Band, the San Simon/Pisinemo Band, the Edmund Wilson Band, the San Tan Band, and the Baboquivari District Band at the Third Annual All O'odham Old Time Fiddle Orchestra Contest. Anouncers are Angelo Joaquin (English) and Daniel Joaquin (O'odham). Order of performance is as follows-- Gu-Achi Band / San Simon/Pisinemo Band / Edmund Wilson Band / Baboquivari District Band / San Tan Band / Edmund Wilson Band. Transcripts and related information available in files 86.3/R.1 and 86.3/R.2. Collected by James S. Griffith, Ajit Aserappa, and David Griffith at Wa:k Pow Wow at San Xavier Mission, Tucson, Arizona. 2 sound tape reels, analog, 7 in. (Box 86.3, Folder R.1, R.2)
  - Francisco Rodriguez and Manuel Rivera, Three corridos de la Revolucion Mexicana, August 22, 1986; Tape contains recording of corridos performed by Rodriguez and Rivera with guitar accompaniment... Grancisca Villa -- El Corrido de Felipe Angeles -- El Dorado de Villa... Related material and printed texts available in file 86.22/M.1. Collected by James S. Griffith at El Pueblo Neighborhood Center Library in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 86.22, Folder R.1)
  - Leonardo Yanez, Corridos, August 22, 1986; Tape contains corridos performed by Yanez with 12-string guitar accompaniment... Asesinto de Pancho Villa -- Renuncia de Don Porteris Diaz a la Presidencia de la Republisa Mexicanos -- El Corrido de Jose Lopez Portillo -- El Mora de Campas -- Que Say Plevelo... Related material availalble in file 86.22/M.2. Collected by James S. Griffith at El Pueblo Neighborhood Center Library in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 86.22, Folder R.2)
  - Leonardo Yanez, Corridos, August 22, 1986; xx (Box 86.22, Folder R.3)
  - Antonio Federico, Selection of Corridos de la Revolución Mexicana, July 27, 1986; Tape contains corridos sung by Federico and accompanied by Oscar Miranda, Richard Morales, James S. Griffith and Alfredo Nunez...Corridos de Durango -- Valentin de la Sierra -- El General Santa Cruz -- Gabino Barrera -- Untitled -- Al Ver Que te Vas. Collected by David Teckawa and Nancy Ranke at the Tucson Museum of Art in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 10 in. (Box 86.22, Folder R.4)
  - Clifford Head, Banjo music, September 6, 1986; This tape replaces 82.16/R.1 and contains banjo tunes performed by Head... Spanish fandango #2 -- Jesse James -- Jesse James (2) -- Christmas time -- Darling Nellie Gray -- Tommy don't go -- Cacklin' hen -- Nobody's business -- Old Joe Clark -- Redwing... Transcript available in file 86.23/R.1. Collected by James S. Griffith and Roberto STabel at Geronimo's Castle Bar in Bowie, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 in. (Box 86.23, Folder R.1)
  - Fourth Annual All O'odham Old Time Fiddle [Orchestra] Band Contest, Wa:k Pow Wow, March 7, 1987; Tapes contain program and performances from the Fourth Annual All O'odham Old Time Fiddle Orchestra Band Contest. Participants include the Edmund Wilson Group, the Nolic Band, the San Tan Band, the Topowa Band, and the Schuk Doag Band. The program is introduced by Angelo Joaquin and Mike Enis. The program is as follows-- Edmund Wilson Group / Nolic Band / San Tan Band / Solo, by Daniel Joaquin / Topowa Band / Schuk Doag Band. Collected by James S. Griffith at the Wa:k Pow Wow at San Xavier Mission in Tucson, Arizona. 2 sound tape reels, analog, 7 in. (Box 87.8, Folder R.1, R.2)
  - Fifth Annual All O'odham Old Time Fiddle Orchestra Contest, March 5, 1988; Tapes include performances by the Schuk Doag Good Old Boys Band, the Gila River San Tan Band, the Edmund Wilson Group, the Nolic Band, Wa:k Old-Time Good-Timers, and the San Xavier Band at the Fifth Annual All O'odham Old Time Fiddle Orchestra Contest. Announcers are Angelo Joaquin, Jr.(English) with Mike Enis and Daniel Joaquin (O'odham). Order of performance is as follows-- Nolic Band / Wa:k Old-Time Good-Timers / San Xavier Band/Edmund Wilson Group / Schuk Doag Good Ol' Boys / Gila River San Tan Band / Schuk Doag Good Ol' Boys. Related material is available in file 88.11/R.1. Collected by James Griffith at the Wa:k Pow Wow at San Xavier Mission in Tucson, Arizona. 3 sound tape reels, analog, 7 in. (Box 88.11, Folder R. 1, R.2, R.3)
  - St. John's Mandolin and Guitar Society, Selections, January 22, 1976; Tape contains songs performed by the St. John's Mandolin and Guitar Society of St. John's, Arizona... Grand old flag medley -- Sweet Daisy Dee -- Our hometown... Related material is available in file 88.14/M.1 and a cassette is available at 88.14/C.1. Collected by James S. Griffith in St. John's, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 5 in. (Box 88.14, Folder R.1)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Dewey Farr, Selections, January 22, 1976; Tape contains songs performed by Mr. and Mrs. Dewey Farr of St.John's, Arizona...Pretty little dear -- I had but fifty cents... Related material available in file 88.14/M.1. Collected by James S. Griffith in St. John's, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 5 in. (Box 88.14, Folder R.2)
  - Callie's Orchestry, Selections, January 22, 1976; Tape contains songs performed by Callie's Orchestry (a female quartet) of St. John's, Arizona... Waltz medley of Wild Irish Rose and Mockingbird Hill -- Dance medley of Redwing/When the moon shines on the mountains/Varsouvianna -- Turkey in the straw -- Irish washerwoman -- You are my sunshine -- It's a long way to Tipperary... Related material available in file 84.14/M.1. Collected by James S. Griffith in St. John's, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 5 in. (Box 88.14, Folder R.3)
  - Sixth Annual All O'odham Old Time Fiddle [Orchestra] Contest, Wa:k Pow Wow, March 4, 1989; Tapes contain performances by the Schuk Doag Good Old Time Boys, the San Tan Band, and the Gu-Achi Fiddlers at the Sixth Annual All O'odham Old Time Fiddle Orchestra Contest. Announcers are Angelo Joaquin, Daniel Joaquin and Mike Enis. Program is in English and O'odham. The order of the program is as follows-- Schuk Doag Good Old Time Boys / San Tan Band / Gu-Achi Fiddlers / San Tan Band. Manuscripts are available in file 89.20/R.1.T. and 89.20/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith at the Wa:k Pow Wow at San Xavier Mission in Tucson, Arizona. 2 sound tape reels, analog, 7 in. (Box 89.20, Folder R.1, R.2)
  - Frank Shinn, Interview, November 16, 1989; Tape contains an interview with Shinn regarding his work during World War II as a United States Marine Corps Recruiter. Shinn recruited Navajo Indians in Arizona to be part of the First 29 Navajo Code Talkers for the Marines. Transcript available in file 89.22/R.1.T. Collected by Zonnie Gorman. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 in. (Box 89.22, Folder R.1.T)
  - Eugene Crawford, Interivew, March 15, 1990; Tape contains interview with Crawford as he describes his boot camp and war experiences during World War II as part of the United States Marine Corps First 29 Navajo Code Talkers. Transcript available in file 90.6/R.1.T. Collected by Zonnie Gorman at the University of New Mexio in Gallup, New Mexico. 2 sound tape reels, analog, 7 in. (Box 90.6, Folder R.1a; R.2b)
  - Eugene Crawford, Interivew, March 16, 1990; Tape contains interview with Gorman as he describes boot camp, development of the Navajo code, battle experiences, being wounded and his eventual recovery during World War II as part of the United States Marine Corps First 29 Navajo Code Talkers. Transcript available in file 90.6/R.3.T. Collected by Zonnie Gorman at the University of New Mexio in Gallup, New Mexico. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 in. (Box 90.6, Folder R.3)
  - Dean Wilson, Interview, April 21, 1990; Tapes include interview with Wilson as he describes his United States Marine Corps experiences during World War II as part of the First 29 Navajo Code Talkers. Wilson discusses his recruitment, boot camp training, development of the Navajo code, and war experiences in Guadalcanal. Transcripts available in files 90.10/R.1.T. and 90.10/R.2.T. Collected by Zonnie Gorman at the University of New Mexio in Gallup, New Mexico. 2 sound tape reels, analog, 7 in. (Box 90.10, Folder R.1, R.2)
  - Zonnie Gorman, Interview, January 18, 1991; Tape includes interview with Frank Shinn, first Navajo Code-Talker Recruitor. Transcripts available in files 91.28/R 1.T. Collected by Zonnie Gorman. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 in. (Box 91.28, Folder tape not located 4/24/01; unknown if tape accessioned)
  - Wilber "Cap" Lehman and Sally Bennett, Fiddle tunes, August 20, 1993; Tape contains interview with and fiddle tunes performed by Lehman with guitar accompaniment by Sally Bennett. Recording was made at Lehman's home. Songs include: Buffalo gals -- Whistling Rufus -- Bill Bailey -- Lady of the lake -- Down yonder -- Johann Persnippen/Swedish schottisch -- German schottisch -- Have I told you lately (that I love you) -- Untitled -- Sally Goodin -- Jump up Susan -- Jump up Susan (2) -- Untitled -- When you and I were young, Maggie. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 93.23, Folder R.1)
  - Wilber "Cap" Lehman and Sally Bennett, Fiddle tunes, August 20, 1993; Tape 2 of 3 contains interview with and fiddle tunes performed by Lehman with guitar accompaniment by Sally Bennett. Recording was made at Lehman's home. Songs include: Redwing -- Silver bells -- Goodnight waltz -- Irish washerwoman -- McCloud's reels -- San Antonio Rose -- Chicken reel -- Ragtime Annie -- Stoney Point. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 93.23, Folder R.2)
  - Wilber "Cap" Lehman and Sally Bennett, Fiddle tunes, August 20, 1993; Tape 3 of 3 contains two recordings of the song, "Mexican Border Tune" performed by Lehman on the fiddle with guitar accompaniment by Sally Bennett. Recording was made at Lehman's home. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 93.23, Folder R.3)
  - Les Keith, Interview and banjo tunes, December 11, 1977; Tape contains vocals and banjo tunes performed by Keith... Bound to ride -- Robber settler -- Shortnin' bread -- Hobo Bill's last ride -- TB blues -- Blind lemon song/Matchbox blues/Old colored man blues. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 10 in. (Box 94.22, Folder R.1)
  - Les Keith, Interview and banjo tunes, December 11, 1977; Tape contains interview and banjo tunes performed by Keith... songs include: Cluck old hen -- Sally Johnson -- Cacklin' hen/Old hen cackled. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 10 in. (Box 94.22, Folder R.2)
  - Les Keith, Interview and banjo tunes, December 30, 1976; Tape contains vocals and banjo tunes performed by Keith. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 15 ips, 10 in. (Box 94.22, Folder R.3)
  - Tucson Old Time Fiddlers’ Contest, undated; Contents and performer list available at 97.63/M.1. Taped recording of the Tucson Old Time Fiddlers’ Contest, 19 February 1967, Tucson, AZ. Recorded on four reel tapes, with call numbers 97.63/R.1-4. Collected by James S. Griffith. 4 sound tapes, 7 in. (Box 97.63, Folder R.1-R.4)
  - Lydia Mendoza, Studio master reel tapes, undated; 12 studio master tape reels of songs recorded by Lydia Mendoza. Collected by James S. Griffith. 12 sound reels. (Box 97.64, Folder R.1-R.12)
  - Bill Hensley, Bill Hensley master reel tapes, undated; Collected by James S. Griffith and Keith Cunningham. (Box 98.10, Folder R.1)
  - Tucson Heritage Experience festival workshop stage, Reel tapes of the T.H.E. festival workshop stage, undated; 2 tape reel boxes (tape reels 4-5) are unlabelled and may be blank. Griffith did not check them before including them in the archives. SWFC has not obtained a release for this material. Reel tapes of the T.H.E. festival workshop stage, 1996, which includes the corrido contest; 5 reel tapes, 3 3/4 ips, half track, tails out, mono. Collected by James S. Griffith. (Box 98.18, Folder R.1-R.5)
  - 3 reel tapes of Tohono O'Odham music, August 22, 1981; 3 Rivers Drum (pow wow); Desert Indian singers and dancers (Danny Lopez, leader); Joaquin Brothers waila band. Collected by John Crouch. (Box 98.24, Folder R.1-R.3)